Steven Rodriguez

8222 Ridgetop Dr San Antonio, TX 78230 (210) 445-1428 srrodrig.rodriguez@gmail.com

Summary

12 years of experience in the electronics field with extensive experience in troubleshooting electronic equipment and performing maintenance and calibrations. 3 years working with electro-pneumatic and robotic systems in a detail driven industrial environment. 3 years as a frac E-tech/Mechanic where I learned the importance of safety-first operations. Excel equally working in a team setting or alone with little to no supervision.

Work Experience

2017-2020 Electronics Field Technician

Halliburton

- * Drew from all aspects of all my prior experience in order to provide stellar onsite electronic support for all frac equipment on location and IT equipment onboard frac van.
- * Performed mechanic field maintenance daily:
- * Performed engine diagnostics using Cummins Insite and CAT ET
- * Performed mid-level engine and transmission repairs:
 - Changed solenoids
 - Replaced temp, speed, position, and pressure sensors
 - Replaced right angle drives and drive shafts
- *Adjusted sand conveyor belts when necessary.
- *Resolved Control Area Network issues by diagnosing faulty sensors, logic controllers, and software incompatibilities.

2016-2017 Cable Technician

Blackbox Networking

- * Installed network infrastructure for Booz Allen, Google, USAA
- * Set up server racks, ran and terminated ethernet cables
- * Installed cell phone repeater networks for Verizon throughout the UTHSC campus

2006-2009 Engineering Technician

Samsung Austin Semiconductor

- * Performed basic and advanced robot calibration and repairs
- * Isolated and replaced faulty mechanisms in complex electro-pneumatic systems

- * Calibrated and maintained a variety of motion, water, and pressure sensors
- * Used software to manipulate mechanical functions with attention to safety
- * Responded to customer trouble calls and complaints in a courteous manner
- * Managed time and resources due to a fast paced, high pressure environment
- * Clearly communicated all equipment issues to senior engineers and oncoming shift technicians as well as recorded and described all work and job progress in a maintenance database.
- * Assisted engineers in setup and testing of experimental new components and software.

2000-2006 Electronics Technician

U.S. Navy

- * Performed preventive and repair maintenance on an array of equipment including:
- UHF/VHF transmitters/receivers

-Telephone lines

- Fiber optic lines for LAN system

- -Surface and air search radars
- * Identified equipment malfunctions and diagnosed to component and modular level using schematics and/or blueprints
- * Conducted precise equipment calibrations on test equipment and radios
- * Responsible for ordering and tracking parts while adhering to budget constraints
- * Managed the installation and final testing of over 200 devices during a major communication system upgrade.
- *Worked under strict FAA guidelines, where attention to detail is imperative.

Education

UTSA- Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp UTSA - engineering courses US Navy Electronics Technician "A" School

Technical Skills

Fluent in:

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- JQuery
- Node
- MySql
- MongoDB
- Express

Night In – App designed to let user choose from supplied options of cocktails, recipes, and movies based on user criteria. HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery.

https://cascutter.github.io/Project-1-Night-In/

Samurai Swap Meet – Ebay inspired app lets users shop and post samurai items for sale. Features sign in verification and image upload. Fullstack. Handlebars, Javascript, Jquery, Node, Express, MySql.

https://samuraiswapmeet.herokuapp.com/

ReadMe Generator – This program is run on the terminal via node and simply prompts the user to answer questions about their project and creates a well formatted readme.md document. https://github.com/steverodrig/ReadMe-Generator